Guide to the Ivo J. Lederer Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ivo J. Lederer papers
1954-1962
SC0163
Lederer, Ivo J.
1 Linear feet
Notes compiled for a study published later as YUGOSLAVIA AT THE PARIS PEACE CONFERENCE: A STUDY IN FRONTIER MAKING (1963).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Ivo J. Lederer, 1977.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of history at Stanford (1965-1977).
Description of the Collection
Notes compiled for a study published later as YUGOSLAVIA AT THE PARIS PEACE CONFERENCE: A STUDY IN FRONTIER MAKING (1963).
Access Terms
Lederer, Ivo J.; Lederer, Ivo J.; Stanford University. Department of History. Students.; Stanford University. Department of History. -- General subdivision--Faculty.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Lazic and Dincic mission (Box 1)
  - Seton-Watson articles (Box 1)
  - CVijic (Box 1)
  - Yugoslav Committee (Box 1)
  - Adriatic - Background (Box 1)
  - Yugoslavia Memoranda and statistics (Box 1)
  - Banat, Treaty of Bucharest, Rumania (Box 1)
  - 1914 (Box 1)
  - 1915 (Box 1)
  - 1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917 (Box 1)
  - 1918 (Box 1)
  - Vesnic mission, 14 points, LL. GCO (Box 1)
  - USA, World War and Treaty of london (Box 1)
  - Pact of Rome, etc. (Box 1)
  - The Inquiry (Box 1)
  - US Policy up to May 29 Declaration (Box 1)
  - Serbia's choice, Arts and controversy (Box 1)
  - Yugoslav revolution/ Geneva Conference (Box 1)
  - Italian memos/claims (Box 1)
  - Italian subversion/ Miles-King mission (Box 1)
  - 1919 (Box 1)
  - Adriatic Quest - sketched (Box 1)
  - January - February 1919 (Box 1)
  - Ljubljana incident, February - March 1919 (Box 1)
  - Commission on Yugoslav affairs to April 6, 1919 (Box 1)
  - April - June 1919 (Box 1)
  - July - December 1919 (Box 1)
  - Conference Commissions (Box 1)
  - Non-territorial questions (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Trurnbic Papers, 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1919 Jan (Box 1)
  - 1919 Feb (Box 1)
  - 1919 Mar (Box 1)
  - 1919 Apr (Box 1)
  - 1919 May (Box 1)
  - June - July 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1919 Aug (Box 1)
  - September - october 1919 (Box 1)
  - November - December 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920 Jan (Box 1)
  - February - March 1920 (Box 1)
  - April - May 1920 (Box 1)
  - June - July 1920 (Box 1)
  - August - September 1920 (Box 1)
  - October - November 1920 (Box 1)
  - Post - Rapallo (Box 1)
  - Trurnbic Papers - miscellany (Box 1)
  - Trurnbic Papers - Albania (Box 1)
  - Trurnbic Papers - completed (Box 1)
  - Pre-1919 (Box 1)
  - Introduction (Box 1)
  - Italian occupation (Box 1)
  - Recognition/ occupation/ Italian politics/ Fiune affair (Box 1)
  - Sforza-Sonnino/ January-June 1918 (Box 1)
  - Pasic (Box 1)
  - First Yugoslav government (Box 1)
  - Recognition (Box 1)
  - Yugoslav delegation (Box 1)
  - Internal developments, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Yugoslav claims and Verseilles (Box 1)
  - Conference: general and miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Montenegro (Box 1)
  - Yillgoslav volunteers (Box 1)
  - Bibliography (Box 1)
  - 1920 (Box 1)
  - Notes on sessions of Peace Conference and Yugoslav delegation at (Box 1)
  - Peace Conference, January 10, 1919 - January 7, 1920 (Box 1)